it’s interesting to see what roof insulation does
The new cabin is still full of snow,
And the other ones are almost twawed out
I think it's the installation.
That one has direct
airflow underneath every stone.
So the warmer temperature
can come through.
That's more sealed. So
it's a big difference.
I'm gonna make some new garden beds.
I wanted to do that last year, but,
because of my back problems, then
I couldn't really work on the garden.
I build this one right in the beginning
from some leftover wood that I found here.
That's all rotten.
And it's also not in a good place because,
I need this space to, to turn the car.
Especially with the trailer.
I need a bit more space
to make the turn and ride back up.
So I think I'll position them,
I'm gonna make two,
just over here,
and, it's gonna need a little fence
around it, because,
in the past years,
we have, wild boar digging around.
Last year, I planted potatoes,
but it was all dug up by wild boar.
So it needs to be,
it needs to have a fence.
And also if I get new chickens.
They're going to roam freely.
So it should be closed off
Might do some work this year.
Also on the solar array
Because in winter it's always difficult.
I dug these gutters here in front.
So when you have just
a little bit of snow, it will slide off
and then you're good.
But with a lot of snow,
it needs to be deeper.
Still works fine.
I mean, the panels are old,
maybe 20 years old now, so
I’m also thinking on upgrading these
but especially the landscaping.
So this hill in front needs to lower a bit.
I was just checking, the garden beds
they're not too high.
But when this packs snow
it blocks the solar panels also a bit
But if it's really a lot of snow.
So yeah.
Improving everything bit by bit
make it better.
Yeah, yeah.
Because
in the winter,
this bit too high, too much snow.
And then it's problem
for the solar panels.
So I want to
grade this down a bit.
That means that,
the grass has to come off
and that’s hard work
Because it needs to be cut loose.
Okay, so you said multiple things,
which is the first thing we should do.
The first layer like stones?
because also the grass can be...
No, not stones
this can be made small
It could go to the bottom, especially here
because this grass
will also just rot and dissapear
not sure if it’s going to rain
Oh, but if we go now, maybe,
let's put it inside
it’s not heavy, just big
So they work also with the university
to protect and...
How to say it,
make this species protected and help survive
Yeah.
these are other breeds we raise,
this is Sussex and Amrock
And then we had one,
like one of the cheetah.
No, it was not.
I know that the these.
we had a grey one
They’re English and American breeds
Yeah, we had something
like this. The first chickens
in the first year.
look at those feather from upcloase
They are really easy
White and red one, ah ok
this is the breed they are raising
Ah, Okay. Oh, wow
That’s a special one, that’s the breeding hen
So she's the one that's, Yeah.
The breeder
hi, guys!
they’re so cute!
Bianca di Saluzzo, Millefiori Rossa
Bionda di Villanova
So these are all Bianca di Saluzzo
Yes, this was the first batch of Bianca di Saluzzo
who wants to come home with us?
Don’t be too excited
Put her in the box too
oh they’re so pretty!
Your new home!
They're dirty from the box
Hi girls, welcome in your home!
This is my favourite
She's beautiful. Yeah.
And big too
She's also so soft
They’re dirty from the poop
You have a big butt
And the important thing is,
is that they find the water.
To get to the water you have to climb there
Yeah, yeah, shall we put it on the ground?
It's freezes in the night. Ah you’re right
They'll figure it out.
It's like this, right?
this direction?
Like this?
Yeah.
don’t make me laugh
They're getting accustomed to their new home
They had some beautiful chickens there
My favorite were the Millefiori Piemontese which are the speckled...
black and white hens
They're very beautiful.
But they only had adults and very young chicks,
and they need to grow a little bit more.
So I think we'll pick those up in,
in a month or so.
These are more, international breeds.
The white one is a Sussex,
the Lohmann Brown,
and I think the black one was an Amrock
I'm sure they have different names
from wherever you're from.
But yeah, it was interesting to see.
So we'll pick up,
I think three more in a month or so.
Also,
Bionda Piemontese, that's also local breed
what's it called?
Bianca de Saluzzo, I think.
So we'll have three more and we'll probably breed a few as well when it warms up.
Still freezing in the night,
so it's too early for that.
The roof trim is now finished.
Next week I'll start with walls, finishing those
Does the garden beds
are going to be filled up.
And then we'll still wait with,
planting greens
because it's still too cold.
But yeah,
scaffolding is all down.
I'm leaving the bit up that is...
the roof for the mortar
I’m going to be pointing the walls
after the walls are finished.
So I need to, still a lot of mortar
And then I'm looking into a floor as well,
because I want to have a bit
more of a finished floor.
Right now, it's concrete,
and it's not very level.
If I want to put machines in there
and workbenches, I want everything
to be perfectly level. So.
And, workshop floor needs to be cleaned out often.
So something a bit more smooth
maybe I'm going to look into
something like a self-leveling mortar.
Or maybe I tile it,
find some beautiful tiles that fit in there.
I have to look into that